Alar Akilbekov

. +7-778-001-0906 | ■ alar.akilbekov@gmail.com | in alar-akilbekov | • Alar-q

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in Data Science, including research and development of algorithms and applications based on machine learning techniques aimed at solving real-world problems. I also have experience in system architecture design and web development. Fluent in English, Russian and Kazakh. Participated in team projects on development and implementation of solutions. I want to contribute to the development of software solutions.

SKILLS

Machine Learning: Deep Learning, Python, Numpy, Pytorch, OpenCV, MatPlotLib, SciKit, Keras etc. Java: OOP, DL4J, OpenCV, Android, Spring Boot, AOP, Maven, Gradle

JavaScript: Functional Programming, NodeJS, Express, React, Webpack, Mongoose, Sequelize, Socket.io Databeses: MongoDB, GraphQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, SQL procedures/transactions, migrations

Other: C++, Go, REST API, WebSocket, RabbitMQ, Git, Docker, CI/CD, Testing, Azure, Microservice

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | Concierge Service Astana - Almaty, Kazakhstan | Dec 2022 - Jul 2023

- Developed MVP web-platform for relationship management, and with a team of managers, designers and developers, we transformed the business from offline to online.
- Done: Software and Database design, Order process, Messenger with text, multimedia and interactive messages, Local and OAuth Authentication, Local File-Storage, External APIs Integration.
- Used: MERN, SPA, React Router, Context, Socket.io, Webpack, Babel, Git, Docker, CI/CD, Azure.

Data Scientist | KazMunaiGas Engineering

Astana, Kazakhstan | Jan 2022 - May 2022

- Developed internal algorithms for processing, analysis, interpretation, visualization and prediction.
- Used: Python and the Numpy, OpenCV, MatPlotLib, PyTorch and other libraries

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Software Engineering, Astana IT University	Astana, Kazakhstan 2021 - 2024
Secondary School, Zhas Daryn specialised school	Pavlodar, Kazakhstan 2021

PROJECTS & RESEARCHES

- Dysgraphia Diagnosis: a research on application of Deep Learning technologies
- Tensor Library: an analogue to math and ML libraries like NumPy or PyTorch from scratch in Java
- Game framework: a 2D/3D framework for android games using canvases and OpenGL ES
- RSA and EDS: RSA encryption and Electronic Digital Signature using modular arithmetic in Java

Competitions & Hackathons

- NU Datathon: Classification of genuine and fictional cars - best model accuracy	2023
- AITU Project Challenge 14: Web-platform development - I place and 1.000.000 tenge	2023
- AITU Project Challenge 9: Sequential series classification - I place	2022
- School research projects: Handwritten text recognition - I place at the national level	2021

Алар Акильбеков

. +7-778-001-0906 | ■ alar.akilbekov@gmail.com | in alar-akilbekov | • Alar-q

Резюме

Программный инженер с опытом работы в области Data Science, включая исследование и разработку алгоритмов и приложений на основе методов машинного обучения, направленных на решение реальных задач. Есть опыт проектирования системной архитектуры и веб-разработки. Свободно владею английским, русским и казахским языками. Участвовал в командных проектах по разработке и внедрению ПО. Я хочу внести свой вклад в разработке программных продуктов.

Навыки

Machine Learning: Deep Learning, Python, Numpy, Pytorch, OpenCV, MatPlotLib, SciKit, Keras etc. Java: OOP, DL4J, OpenCV, Android, Spring Boot, AOP, Maven, Gradle

JavaScript: ΦΠ, NodeJS, Express, React, Webpack, Mongoose, Sequelize, Socket.io

Базы данных: MongoDB, GraphQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, SQL процедуры/транзакции, миграции Другие: CPP, Go, REST, WebSocket, RabbitMQ, Git, Docker, CI/CD, Тесты, Azure, Микросервисы

Опыт работы

Full Stack Разработчик | Concierge Service

Астана - Алматы | Дек 2022 - Июл 2023

- Разработал MVP веб-платформу. Вместе с командой перевели офлайна бизнес в онлайн.
- Выполнил: Проектирование программного обеспечения и базы данных, процесс оформления заказа, мессенджер с текстовыми, мультимедийными и интерактивными сообщениями, локальная и OAuth аутентификация, локальное файловое хранилище, интеграция внешних API.
- Texh.: MERN, SPA, React Router, Context, Socket.io, Webpack, Babel, Git, Docker, CI/CD, Azure.

Data Scientist | КазМунайГаз Инжиниринг

Астана | Янв 2022 - Май 2022

- Разрабатывал внутренние алгоритмы обработки, анализа, интерпретации и прогнозирования.
- Texh.: Python и библиотеки Numpy, OpenCV, MatPlotLib, PyTorch и другие

Образование

Бакалавр программной инженерии, Astana IT University Среднее общее образование, специализированная школа Жас Дарын

Астана | 2021 - 2024

Павлодар | 2021

ПРОЕКТЫ И ИССЛЕДОВАНИЯ

- Диагностирование Дисграфии: исследование по применению технологий глубокого обучения
- **Библиотека Тензоров**: аналог математических и ML-библиотек, таких как NumPy или PyTorch
- Игра: 2D/3D фреймворк для игр под андроид, использующий canvas-ы и OpenGL ES
- RSA и ЭЦП: Шифрование RSA и Электронная Цифровая Подпись на Java

Конкурсы и Хакатоны

- NU Datathon: Классификация автомобилей - наилучшая точность модели	
- AITU Project Challenge 14: Разработка веб-платформы - I место и 1.000.000 тенге	2023
- AITU Project Challenge 9: Классификация последовательных рядов - I место	2022
- Конкурс научных проектов: Распознавание рукописного текста - І место	2021